Moshood Rafiu

Software Engineer

Innovative and technically-astute software engineer with a 5-year Computer Engineering degree and 2+ years of experience. As a creative and ambitious software engineer with a talent for critical reasoning and problemsolving, my passion is to contribute to how the internet is progressing and how web applications are evolving. I enjoy working collaboratively but I can also work independently.

Contact

Address

Mowo, Lagos, 103101

Phone

+234 814 425 934

E-mail

rafiumoshoodolakunle@gmail. com

GitHub

https://github.com/MoshoodR afiu

Portfolio

https://moshoodrafiu.netlify.app

Skills

HTML

CSS (Bootsrap, Tailwind CSS)

JavaScript (VueJS, jQuery)

PHP (Laravel, Livewire)

MySQL

Work History

2021-07 -Present

Full Stack Developer

Cultuzz Digital Media GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- Optimized the speed of booking channels mapper by 50%.
- Integrated products with multiple property management applications.
- Implement designs using modern web technologies.
- Contribute ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Review code, fix bugs and improve application performance.

2021-11 -2022-07

Contract Full Stack Developer

BigCommand LLC, Wilmington, Delaware, USA

- Rebuilt the video hosting channel and reduced channel page load time by 70%.
- Improved the watch history of videos for analytics purposes.
- Developed public APIs for video hosting application users.
- Built a viral campaign feature for new and existing users.

AWS

Git

Relevant Courses

Data Structures and Algorithms

Database System Design and Management

Object Oriented Programming (OOP)

Cloud Fundamentals

2021-03 - Full S 2021-06 Swoot

Full Stack Developer

Sweet Spot Labs, Tokyo, Japan

- Developed a new modern website for the company.
- Developed multiple crawler scripts to compile, transverse and manipulate lists of orthodontists in Japan from various public directories to suit the company's needs.

2020-07 -2021-02

Backend Developer Intern

Atata57.com, Ikeja, Lagos

- Balanced design principles and technology standards with product timelines and customerspecific requirements.
- Fixed bugs and clean up code in other to improve application performance.
- Contributed actively to the development and management of REST APIs using PHP (Laravel) technology, and MySQL database.
- Wrote detailed documentation for the developed API endpoints.

Education

2016-12 -

2022-07

Bachelor Of Science: Electronic and Computer Engineering

Lagos State University - Lagos Graduated with a First Class Honours

2022-05 **–** 2022-09

Nano Degree: Cloud DevOps Engineering

Udacity